<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>V for VERBOSE</title><link>http://i90rr.github.io</link>
<description>-v is the sexiest flag</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 05:19:45 -0300</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 05:19:45 -0300</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://i90rr.github.io/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Title on this line
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The rest of the text file is a <strong>Markdown</strong> blog post. The process will continue
as soon as you exit your editor.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_keep-this-tag-format.html'>keep-this-tag-format</a>, <a href='tag_tags-are-optional.html'>tags-are-optional</a>, <a href='tag_beware-with-underscores-in-markdown.html'>beware-with-underscores-in-markdown</a>, <a href='tag_example.html'>example</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://i90rr.github.io/title-on-this-line.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
<a href="https://twitter.com/share" class="twitter-share-button" data-text="&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;" data-url="http://i90rr.github.io/title-on-this-line.html"
 data-via="_i90rr"
>Tweet</a>	<script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","twitter-wjs");</script>
</p>
]]></description><link>http://i90rr.github.io/title-on-this-line.html</link>
<guid>http://i90rr.github.io/./title-on-this-line.html</guid>
<dc:creator>i90rr</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 04:07:55 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Go code with Atom editor on GNU+Linux
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Today I will be sharing a workaround I implemented to make third-party Go packages work with an standard Atom editor installation.</p>

<p>Lately I started to flirt with <a href="https://atom.io" title="A hackable text editor for the 21st Century">Atom</a> after my boss suggested me to give it a try for working with our Puppet infrastructure implementation - thanks for the tip Adam!</p>

<p>Truth is that I have tried Atom in the past when it was at its early stages and while I saw at the time the project had a lot of potential there were too many issues, mainly related to performance, that pushed me away of it thus missing the opportunity to give it a fair try - for the record, I'm an avid Emacs user and lately a <a href="http://spacemacs.org" title="A community-driven Emacs distribution - The best editor is neither Emacs nor Vim, it's Emacs *and* Vim!">Spacemacs</a> fan, more on it on an upcoming post. </p>

<p>Time went on and now Atom is a quite mature and feature-complete text editor. While it's difficult for me to digest the idea that it is in fact a Chromium-based web browser tweaked to work as a text editor, and nontheless how bloated it "has" to be given its foundations and regardless all the work being done to optimize its performance, I can understand why the developers went this way: given its roots I suppose that most of them if not the vast majority are web-oriented developers, so to them this is a natural direction. Now, to be truthful, Atom 1.3.2 on my Fedora 23 system <em>runs incredible snappy</em>.</p>

<p>Atom has a big community that continuously adds new features in the form of plugins. As with other programming languages there are some Go packages that can (and will) make a difference at the moment of diving into the editor to start hammering the keyboard. </p>

<p>So far I found these two third-party packages very useful:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>go-config</strong>: detects installed Go runtime(s), tools and configurations making them available for use by other packages</li>
<li><strong>go-plus</strong>: adds 'gocode', 'gofmt', 'goimports', 'go vet', 'golint', 'go build' and 'go test' functionality for the Go language</li>
</ul>

<p>They both install well, but making them work is a different story.</p>

<hr />
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://i90rr.github.io/coding-in-go-with-atom-in-gnulinux.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
<a href="https://twitter.com/share" class="twitter-share-button" data-text="&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;" data-url="http://i90rr.github.io/coding-in-go-with-atom-in-gnulinux.html"
 data-via="_i90rr"
>Tweet</a>	<script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","twitter-wjs");</script>
</p>
]]></description><link>http://i90rr.github.io/coding-in-go-with-atom-in-gnulinux.html</link>
<guid>http://i90rr.github.io/./coding-in-go-with-atom-in-gnulinux.html</guid>
<dc:creator>i90rr</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 01:27:00 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
We are in business (finally)
</title><description><![CDATA[
<div style="text-align:right">
<img src="https://avatars1.githubusercontent.com/u/394089?v=3&amp;s=460" alt="The good days..." title="Biking on a cold, sunny day at the oceanside. What could be better?" />
<div style="text-align:left"></p>

<p><strong>About me</strong></p>

<p>Hi, I'm i90rr, welcome to my little corner on the 3w. <br />
I'm a n3rd, I'm also a Unix(-like) SysAdmin passionate about automation, optimization, hardening and F/LOSS. <br />
Among many other things I love to surf. Surfing is a state of mind - like Zen. When you surf, you connect with the world. <em>Pura vida!</em></p>

<p><strong>About this blog</strong>                                                                 </p>

<p>It certainly took me more time than I'd wished to set up this blog but finally here we are. I will permit myself a little bit of indulgence to pat my back, sip some grog and appreciate my endeavor. Good job, me!</p>

<p>I have to warmly thank <a href="https://cardinali.org" title="Ezequiel Cardinali">@ezq</a> who was the one who introduced me to this little cool dude that is <a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/bashblog">bashblog</a> last year when I attended to the <strong>FUDCon 2015</strong> (<em>Fedora Users and Developers Conference</em>) that was held in the month of September in Córdoba, Argentina. It was a fantastic event where I had the chance to meet the extraordinary people that conforms the Fedora community. <em>You really rock guys!</em></p>

<ul>
<li>This blog focuses on IT, yet don't be surprised to find entries about pretty much everything else that catches my attention</li>
<li>It is a static blog, meaning it doesn't rely on any database or dynamic stuff like - <em>ughh</em> - JS and friends</li>
<li>It is made using <em>bashblog</em>, a static site generator written in Bash (duh!)</li>
<li>It is hosted at GitHub Pages (<a href="https://pages.github.com" title="GitHub Pages">go ahead and try it by yourself</a>)</li>
<li>Thanks to being a static blog and being hosted by the kind people at GitHub it is mostly invulnerable to the dangers of the interwebs</li>
<li>It is devilish fast to load since it is made of just <em>markdown</em> and <em>HTML</em></li>
<li>Being light on resources as it is it won't suck your computer dry avid for CPU or GPU cycles and RAM</li>
<li>I agree that my English sucks; on the bright side I'm actively working on getting better at it. If you see anything wrong please leave a comment :)</li>
<li>Last but not least: this blog is meant to be an open hub to learn, to share, to grow and to evolve</li>
</ul>

<p>( What takes us to... )</p>

<p><strong>There's only a couple of rules to follow</strong> (Oh, stop complaining! <em>Some rules</em> are always necessary)                                  </p>

<ul>
<li>When commenting try to not be a dick - no one likes smart-asses. <br />
If you're one you better be brilliant, otherwise GTFOOH - yeah, I have very little patience for BS</li>
<li>Above all, <strong>have fun!</strong></li>
</ul>

<hr />
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://i90rr.github.io/h4we-are-in-business-finallyh4.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
<a href="https://twitter.com/share" class="twitter-share-button" data-text="&lt;Type your comment here but please leave the URL so that other people can follow the comments&gt;" data-url="http://i90rr.github.io/h4we-are-in-business-finallyh4.html"
 data-via="_i90rr"
>Tweet</a>	<script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","twitter-wjs");</script>
</p>
]]></description><link>http://i90rr.github.io/h4we-are-in-business-finallyh4.html</link>
<guid>http://i90rr.github.io/./h4we-are-in-business-finallyh4.html</guid>
<dc:creator>i90rr</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 23:11:00 -0300</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
